Woobin Im

☑ 임우빈
Ph.D. candidate
SGVR Lab @ KAIST

<u>iwbn@kaist.ac.kr</u>

in linkedin.com/in/woobin-im

♠ 402V I8AAAAJ

github.com/iwbn

★ iwbn.github.io/

About

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at KAIST, South Korea. My research is focused on solving **computer vision** problems using **machine learning**. I am especially interested in **motion**, so I have been working on video-related topics.

Research interests: video, optical flow, spacetime, dynamic NeRF, generative models.

Award

- Naver Ph.D Fellowship Award, 2022.
- Finalist at Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea (QIFK), 2020.
- Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award (우수조교상), KAIST, 2019.

Education

• KAIST, Ph.D., Computer Science

2018-current

• KAIST, M.S., Computer Science

2016-2018

o Advisor: Professor Hyun Seung Yang

o Advisor: Professor Sung-Eui Yoon

• Yonsei University, B.S., Computer Science 2012-2016

Work

• CLOVA, NAVER Cloud Corp. (internship)

2023.02-2023.08

Service



• SGVR KAIST Website (Skill: web frontend, Wordpress, PHP)

2018-current

• GPU Cluster (Skill: Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana)

2023-current

Publication

Multi-resolution distillation for self-supervised monocular depth estimation
 Sebin Lee, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon

Pattern Recognition Letters, 2023

• Diffusion Probabilistic Models for Scene-Scale 3D Categorical Data

<u>Jumin Lee</u>, **Woobin Im**, <u>Sebin Lee</u>, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u>

Workshop on Image Processing and Image Understanding (IPIU), 2023

Best Paper Award [arxiv] [github]

• Scenario Generation by Action Scene-Graph Prediction

Woobin Im, <u>Woo Jae Kim</u>, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Software Congress (KSC)*, 2022 [web] [paper]

 Semi-Supervised Learning of Optical Flow by Flow Supervisor Woobin Im, <u>Sebin Lee</u>, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022

[web] [arxiv] [github]

• In-N-Out: Towards Good Initialization for Inpainting and Outpainting

<u>Changho Jo</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC)*, 2021 [web] [arxiv] [github]

• Self-Supervised Visual Odometry via Frame Interpolation

<u>Sebin Lee</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2021 [paper]

• Unsupervised Learning of Optical Flow with Deep Feature Similarity

Woobin Im, <u>Tae-Kyun Kim</u>, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2020

[web] [paper] [github]

• Combined Center Dispersion Loss Function for Deep Facial Expression Recognition

<u>Abhilasha Nanda</u>, **Woobin Im**, <u>Key-Sun Choi</u>, and <u>Hyun Seung Yang</u> <u>Pattern Recognition Letters</u>, 2020 [<u>paper</u>]

• Two-stream Spatiotemporal Feature for Video QA Task

<u>Chiwan Song</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> <u>https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05006</u>, 2019 [arxiv]

Acoustic Material Estimation with Convolutional Neural Network

Doheon Lee, <u>Inkyu An</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2019 [paper]

• An Application of Convolutional-LSTM Network and Video QA

<u>Chiwan Song</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Sung-Eui Yoon</u> *Korea Computer Congress (KCC)*, 2018 [paper]

• Scale-Varying Triplet Ranking with Classification Loss for Facial Age Estimation

Woobin Im, Sungeun Hong, Sung-Eui Yoon, and Hyun S. Yang Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018
[web] [paper] [github]

• CBVMR: Content-Based Video-Music Retrieval Using Soft Intra-Modal Structure Constraint

<u>Sungeun Hong</u>, **Woobin Im**, and <u>Hyun S. Yang</u> *Proceedings of the ACM international conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR)*, 2018

[paper] [video]

• D3: Recognizing dynamic scenes with deep dual descriptor based on key frames and key segments Sungeun Hong, Jongbin Ryu, Woobin Im, and Hyun S. Yang

Neurocomputing, 2018

[paper]

SSPP-DAN: Deep Domain Adaptation Network for Face Recognition with Single Sample Per Person

<u>Sungeun Hong</u>, **Woobin Im**, <u>Jongbin Ryu</u>, and <u>Hyun S. Yang</u> *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP'17), IEEE*, 2017 **Oral** [paper]

Convolutional Texture Networks based on Histogram Pooling

Jongbin Ryu, Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, and Hyun S. Yang

Image-text multi-modal representation learning by adversarial backpropagation

<u>Gwangbeen Park</u> and **Woobin Im** *arXiv preprint arXiv:1612.08354*, 2016

• Deep CNN-based Person Identification using Facial and Clothing Features

<u>Sungeun Hong</u>, **Woobin Im**, Junwoo Park, and <u>Hyun S. Yang</u> Jun 2016, Summer General Conference '16, IEEK, 2016

Patent

- 트리플릿 기반의 손실함수를 활용한 순서가 있는 분류문제를 위한 딥러닝 모델 학습 방법 및 장치 (Using Triplet-based Loss for Training Ordinal Classification Deep Models)
 [US App] [KR App]
- 부분 이미지 기반 객체 판별 방법 및 장치 (Partial Face Based Person Identification Across Poses)
 [KR]
- 도메인 적응 기반 객체 인식 모델 제공 장치 및 방법 (APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR PROVIDING OBJECT RECOGNITION MODEL BASED ON DOMAIN ADAPTATION)
 [KR App]
- 광학 흐름 추정을 위한 딥 유사도 기반 비지도 학습의 컴퓨터 시스템 및 그의 방법 (COMPUTER SYSTEM OF UNSU-PERVISED LEARNING WITH DEEP SIMILARITY FOR OPTICAL FLOW ESTIMATION AND METHOD THEREOF)
 [KR] [US App]

Experience

- Teaching Assistants
 - o GSAG-KAIST Research and Education Program, 1/2019-2/2019
 - o CS206: Data Structure (Spring 2019), 3/2019-6/2019
 - o CS688: Web-Scale Image Retrieval (Fall 2018), 9/2018-12/2018
 - o CS101: Introduction to Programming, 9/2016-12/2017, 9/2018-12/2018
- Undergraduate Research Assistant
 - o DB Lab, Yonsei University, 1/2014-2/2014